Sudie James Simmons

sudiesimmons@aya.yale.edu sudiesimmons.com 203.218.3072 Brooklyn, NY

Skills

Content Strategy
Customer Support
Wireframing
Prototyping
User Research
Research Analysis
Emotional Design

Tools

Sketch
InVision
Balsamiq
Adobe
OptimalSort
Wordpress
Asana

Languages

Italian Spanish

Hobbies

Baking Hiking Reading Shuffleboard Travel

Profile

I have experience in content management, UX design, and organizational operations. I create logical, functional systems to help users better understand their own needs. I instinctively prioritize the concerns, preferences, and anxieties of others, and have sought a career path that relies on empathy and innovation to solve problems creatively.

Experience

Director of Content | Urban Tech | New York, NY | April 2017 - Present

- Facilitating conversion of curriculum from analog to digital.
- Managing alignment of curriculum to Common Core Standards.
- Advising on strategic partnerships.
- Creating blog posts on relevant current events.

Sales Administrator | Fundera | New York, NY | 2015 - 2017

- Built administrative protocol for 30-person Sales team.
- Managed communications between Sales, Operations, and Product teams.
- Collaborated with Product team to create streamlined application process.

Medical Assistant | ENT Center | Stamford, CT | 2013 - 2015

- Obtained and transcribed histories and charting notes for 25 patients daily, totalling 4,000 hours of patient care.
- Tracked short- and long-term patient progress through consistent follow-up.
- Wrote ultrasound protocol currently in use by Stamford hospital system.

Education

CareerFoundry | New York, NY – Front End for Designers, anticipated 2019 CareerFoundry | New York, NY – UX Immersion, 2018 Yale University | New Haven, CT – B.A., Literature, 2013

Events

Moderated *Ladies that UX* panel. Led team at design hackathon for promoting underrepresented communities in tech.